<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Homelab on Alecks</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/homelab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homelab on Alecks</description>
    <image>
      <title>Alecks</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.149.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Alecks 2025</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The state of my Homelab in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/homelab-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/homelab-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently my Homelab is used to run services for personal use, my stuff exposed to the internet and VMs for friends or people in my local community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original goal of this setup was to build a service that lets me cancel all of my vps subscriptions, which so far has succeeded, the next goal is to make the service as reliable or close to as reliable as a proper hosting provider.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I host Linux VMs for people in my Homelab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vps-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vps-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of my Homelab typically sits idle, wasting power. So I had the idea of letting other people run their own linux virtual machines on it, kinda like how gcp offers &amp;ldquo;spot&amp;rdquo; vms for much cheaper as it uses excess compute capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t provide this as a paid service since that comes with a lot of liability and legal documents to protect yourself, so I just offer it as a free service for friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exposing self-hosted applications without a Public IP address</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/exposing-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/exposing-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world everyone could port forward and use an ISP with DDoS Protection and Static IPs, however we don&amp;rsquo;t live in a perfect world. Many people have to deal with things like CGNAT (no public ip) and annoying ISPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are a few &lt;strong&gt;free and paid&lt;/strong&gt; solutions for exposing both web applications and game servers to the internet without port forwarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloudflare-tunnels&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-one/connections/connect-networks/&#34;&gt;Cloudflare Tunnels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a completely free service which supports exposing only web applications to the internet using an application (cloudflared) running on your server which tunnels traffic out and exposes it via the Cloudflare Network&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The perfect home servers - Mini PCs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mini-pcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mini-pcs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I picked up a $100 Lenovo ThinkCentre M710Q off ebay with an i5 7400T, 8GB of ram and a 256GB NVMe SSD to add to my Proxmox cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-good--bad&#34;&gt;The good &amp;amp; Bad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini PCs are built to be small, quiet and power efficient, perfect for a home server. They&amp;rsquo;re also tiny, hence the name meaning they can live pretty much anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, their form factor makes them hard to upgrade for future expandability and hard to add redundant storage to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
